Now, for step two of cleaning data programmatically,
الآن، بالنسبة إلى الخطوة الثانية من مسح البيانات برمجيًا،
we actually get to code.
حصلنا بالفعل على الكود.
Let's convert our cleaning definitions into Python code.
دعونا نحول تعريفات المسح إلى كود Python.
Before we make any modifications to the dataset though,
قبل إجراء أي تعديلات على مجموعة البيانات،
let's make a copy of it so we can access the original data set later.
دعونا ننشئ نسخة منها حتى نتمكن من الوصول إلى مجموعة البيانات الأصلية لاحقًا.
We can do this using Pandas.copy function.
يمكننا فعل ذلك باستخدام دالة Pandas.copy.
And we'll call the data frame that is returned df_clean.
وسنستدعي إطار البيانات الذي ترجعه دالة df_clean.
It's not clean yet, but it soon will be.
إنه ليس نظيفًا بعد، ولكن قريبًا سيكون.
Let's actually attack the non-descriptive column headers issue first because it's easier.
دعونا نهاجم مشكلة عناوين الأعمدة غير الوصفية أولًا، لأنها أسهل.
Let's switch these definitions around
دعونا نبدل هذه التعريفات
and we'll copy and paste the definition below the code header too.
وسننسخ التعريف الموجود ونلصقه أسفل عنوان الكود أيضًا.
This cell has to be a markdown cell to accept text.
يجب أن تكون هذه الخلية، خلية markdown لكي تقبل النصوص.
Let's pull up Google and search rename columns Pandas.
دعونا نسحب Google ونبحث عن إعادة تسمية الأعمدة Pandas.
I'm telling you, half of being a good programmer is searching skills.
أنا أؤكد لكم، نصف المبرمج الجيد يعتمد على مهاراته في البحث.
The first result isn't the Pandas documentation.
النتيجة الأولى ليست وثائق Pandas.
It's actually a stack overflow post.
إنه في الواقع منشور في موقع Stack Overflow.
The answer here must be really helpful.
يجب أن تكون الإجابة هنا مفيدة.
Pause the video and take a second to read this question if you'd like.
أوقفوا مقطع الفيديو وخذوا ثانية من وقتكم لقراءة هذا السؤال إذا أردتم.
Renaming columns and Pandas.
إعادة تسمية الأعمدة و Pandas.
I have a data table using Pandas,
لدي جدول بيانات باستخدام Pandas،
they probably mean DataFrame and column labels
من المحتمل أنهم يقصدون إطار البيانات وتسميات الأعمدة
that I need to edit to replace the original column labels.
التي أريد تعديلها لاستبدال تسميات الأعمدة الأصلية.
Yeah, okay. That sounds like our issue.
حسنًا، نعم. يبدو ذلك نفس مشكلتنا.
And let's scroll down to the most up voted answer.
ودعونا نمرر للأسفل لنصل إلى الإجابة ذات التصويت الأعلى.
Here's the accepted one with the check mark, 740 up votes.
هذه هي الإجابة المقبولة بحوالي 740 صوت.
But there's actually one down here with more, 1263.
ولكن هناك بالفعل إجابة أخرى بالأسفل بأكثر من 1263 صوت.
Again, pause the video and take a second to read this answer if you'd like.
مرة أخرى، أوقفوا مقطع الفيديو وخذوا ثانية من وقتكم لقراءة هذه الإجابة إذا أردتم.
So, use the rename function and refer the columns to be renamed.
إذًا، استخدموا دالة إعادة التسمية وقوموا بالإشارة إلى الأعمدة المراد إعادة تسميتها.
Not all the columns have to be renamed,
لكن ليس كل الأعمدة سيعاد تسميتها،
and it give us two options.
ويعطينا خيارين.
So, I'll copy and paste this one here into our Jupyter Notebook.
لذا، سأنسخ وألصق هذا إلى تطبيق Jupyter notebook.
But again, you shouldn't.
ولكن مرة أخرى، لا يجب عليكم.
Writing the code out will help make you a better programmer.
كتابة الكود ستساعدكم أن تكونوا مبرمجين محترفين.
And we have to make this df_clean because we don't want to modify the original dataset.
ويتعين علينا أن نفعل هذا df_clean لأننا لا نريد تعديل مجموعة البيانات الأصلية.
We want to modify the copy we just made above here.
لكننا نريد تعديل النسخة التي أنشأناها هنا.
Okay, so the answer gave us dummy parameters.
حسنًا، أعطتنا الإجابة معلمات وهمية.
{ 'oldName1' : 'NewName1',
{ 'oldName1' : 'NewName1',
'oldName2' : 'newName2' }.
'oldName2' : 'newName2' }.
In the quiz ahead,
في الاختبار القادم،
replace these with our actual column headers.
استبدلوا هذه بعناوين الأعمدة الفعلية.
Old and New to fix this non-descriptive and misspelled column headers issue.
Old وNew لإصلاح مشكلة عناوين الأعمدة غير الوصفية وغير المكتوبة بصورة صحيحة.